belgianrail.be 2014-11-21

# NMBS/SNCB - Policy concerning privacy on SNCB websites and apps

## Policy concerning privacy on SNCB websites (www.sncb.be, m.sncb.be, www.railtime.be, m.railtime.be) and apps (SNCB and Railtime apps) 

NMBS/SNCB Mobility intends to protect your privacy and the privacy of every visitor in accordance with all legal and other provisions with regard to the protection of privacy.

The visitor to this website is aware of the fact that some data pertaining to him may become known simply by opening this websites. 

### 1\. Scope

NMBS/SNCB Mobility, a directorate of the 'Nationale Maatschappij der Belgische Spoorwegen'/'Société Nationale des Chemins de Fer Belges' (NMBS/SNCB), ensures your privacy and, in this frame, acts in accordance with the provisions of Belgian law concerning the protection of privacy (Law of 8 December 1992 concerning the protection of privacy with regard to the processing of personal data). Read this policy concerning privacy to find out more about the ways in which personal data is collected and processed on this websites (www.sncb.be and m.sncb.be, hereinafter referred to as the "Website") and, if applicable, in the apps ("NMBS/SNCB" and “Railtime” mobile applications available for download on smartphones and smart tablets via app stores, m.sncb.be and www.railtime.be, hereinafter referred to as "Apps").

By buying train tickets for travel in Belgium or for cross-border travel, as well as associated products, and booking services on the Website or Apps, by using the Website or Apps and communicating personal data, you formally agree to the conditions indicated below by virtue of which NMBS/SNCB Mobility collects, processes and transfers personal data and/or (depending on the case) you vouch for the fact that these conditions have been communicated to the people to whom the personal data refers and that these have been accepted by these people.

### 2\. Security

NMBS/SNCB Mobility undertakes to take all the appropriate technical and organisational measures needed to protect your personal data from destruction, loss, involuntary modifications, deterioration or disclosure. 

In order to guarantee this security, NMBS/SNCB Mobility carries out, among other things, regular back-ups.

### 3\. Processing of personal data

3.1. Collection, processing and purpose of personal data on the Website and the Apps

During each visit to the Website or when using the Apps, different personal data and journal files concerning you are collected, namely your IP address, the website from which you were redirected to the Website, the date and duration of your visit, your browser, your operating system, your browsing behaviour and, more specifically, the pages you visit. 

This data is used solely for statistical purposes and in order to analyse and optimise the functioning and use of the Website and the Apps. To that end, NMBS/SNCB Mobility calls upon the services of third parties to which this data is communicated for these purposes.

Whenever your visit is not limited to collecting general information and, more specifically, when, on or via the Website and/or Apps: 

(i) you buy a travel ticket or an associated product,  
(ii) you pay set fines online as a result of a irregularity,  
(iii) you book a service or assistance,  
(iv) you contact NMBS/SNCB Mobility,  
(v) you sign up for a My NMBS/SNCB account,  
(vi) you take part in a contest,  
(vii) you agree to receive the NMBS/SNCB Mobility newsletter and/or other information about the products and services offered by NMBS/SNCB Mobility,  
(viii) you agree to activate certain services when downloading Apps, such as the indication of the nearest station based on your localisation data, the saving of your train times in your agenda, the communication of these times to people of your choice. 

additional data is also requested and/or collected, including, if applicable, your gender, name, e-mail address, current position, password, order history, telephone number, address, language. 

This data is used respectively 

(i) with a view to providing you with a travel ticket, a associated product or service and, if applicable, additional information about this with a view to delivering and following up the corresponding products or services and guarantee the after-sales service;  
(ii) with a view to being able to deal with any of your questions, messages or requests and to reply to them whenever required;   
(iii) with a view to allowing you to pay set fines as a result of a irregularity;  
(iv) with a view to being able to allow you to take full advantage of your My NMBS/SNCB account, which includes a My Train Info subscription (text message when one of your favourite trains is late if you have a valid train card), simplification of certain operations (online assistance request for mobility-impaired passengers, purchase of validations for your train card or Mobib card, . . ., payment of a set fine for an irregularity), access to the order history and to your data for its management, as well as for personalised marketing purposes;  
(v) with a view to allowing you to take part in contests and to informing you about its organisation and outcome;  
(vi) in order to provide you with newsletters;   
(vii) with a view to constantly improving the service offered to you and to adapt it to your needs, in particular by offering personalised services likely to be of interest to you on the basis of customer profiles;  
(viii) with a view to informing you and to allowing you to participate in market research and satisfaction surveys concerning the products and services offered by NMBS/SNCB Mobility;  
(ix) with a view to allowing you to take advantage of the additional services in the Apps, such as the indication of the nearest station based on your localisation data, the saving of your itineraries in your agenda, the communication of these times to people of your choice;

and may, to that end, be transferred to third parties or subcontractors, as explained below in point 3.2.

3.2.    Transfer to third parties

NMBS/SNCB Mobility may transfer certain personal data to third parties, among other things, for the following purposes:

  * in the case of subscriptions combined with other public transport operators (MIVB/STIB, TEC, De Lijn, etc.), NMBS/SNCB Mobility communicates any data these third parties need to carry out their task; 
  * to competent authorities in the frame of imminent or pending legal procedures.

These third parties act as "processing managers" for the execution of this processing or other personal data processing. For further information about this processing, SNCB Mobility also refers you to the applicable privacy policy of these third parties.

NMBS/SNCB Mobility may also transfer some personal data to other individuals or legal persons acting as subcontractors for NMBS/SNCB Mobility. In this case, they only have access to the data they require to carry out their task.

3.3. Transfer abroad 

By using the Website or Apps, or by communicating your personal data to NMBS/SNCB Mobility, you acknowledge and expressly accept that, in the frame of the processing of the personal data mentioned, data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area which do not offer a similar level of protection for personal data.

### 4.    Cookies

The Website uses "cookies", namely small data files which are saved temporarily or permanently on your computer or device by a website's service via the browser, and which simplify, complete and personalise the Website's use.

In your browser, you can deactivate the saving of cookies or remove any cookies saved but this may cause a diminished function, a slowdown in the service, or the inability to use certain parts of the Website. 

For further information about cookies and how to remove them according to the type of browser used, NMBS/SNCB Mobility invites you to refer to the following website:  www.allaboutcookies.org. 

NMBS/SNCB Mobility uses the following cookies:

  1. Strictly necessary cookies are cookies which allow visitors to look at the Website, use the Website's functions (such as your shopping basket when ordering) and access secure and saved sections. If the use of these cookies is deactivated, it may not be possible to use certain parts of the Website correctly. 
  2. Performance cookies are cookies which are designed to collect data concerning the way in which visitors use the Website, such as information about the pages consulted or the number of error messages which have appeared, in order to analyse and optimise use of the Website. 
  3. Functional cookies are cookies which allow SNCB Mobility to remember the choices and preferences (such as the choice of language, etc.) of visitors in order to improve the Website's ease of use and be able to present more relevant information to visitors.   

### 5\. Right to access, adapt and rectify

As provided for by the Law concerning privacy, you have the right, at any time, to freely oppose the processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes, a right to access personal data and a right to correct it and, if necessary, a right to delete it. To that end, you may contact the service responsible at NMBS/SNCB Mobility in writing at the address indicated below, remembering to provide proof of your identity. 

If you have a My NMBS/SNCB account, it is possible for you to manage and modify your data yourself and to choose not to receive e-mails or text messages from NMBS/SNCB Mobility.

### 6.    Contact details

NMBS/SNCB Mobility is a directorate of the 'Nationale Maatschappij der Belgische Spoorwegen'/'Société Nationale des Chemins de Fer Belges' (NMBS/SNCB), a public limited company, rue de France 56, 1060 Brussels (LER Brussels: BE 0203.430.576).

The NMBS/SNCB is responsible for processing this personal data and ensures the confidentiality and security of this data.  

You may contact the NMBS/SNCB (NMBS/SNCB Mobility Directorate) at the following address: Service à la Clientèle de SNCB, Avenue de la Porte de Hal 40, 1060 Brussels, or by electronic mail sent to privacy@b-rail.be. 

NMBS/SNCB Mobility reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time.
